《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
哈里森·纳什·威尔斯博士
Dr. Harrison "Nash" Wells.
我来找一件合成品
I'm searching for an artifact
它恰好含有恒金
that just happens to contain Eternium.
苏·迪尔邦的失踪
The disappearance of Sue Dearbon.
我觉得我从没见过你对一个案子这么投入
I don't think I've ever seen you this devoted to a case.
噬血细胞综合症不仅是我母亲得的病
HLH isn't just my mother's disease.
瑞秋·罗素
挚爱的母亲  1956-2019
它正在杀死我
Now it's killing me.
你也是将死之人  对吗  巴里
You're a dead man, too. Aren't you, Barry?
唯一一条所有人活下来的时间线
The only timeline where everyone survives
就是我死了的那条
was the one where I died.
你们没人可以试着救我
And none of you can try and save me.
对米切·罗梅罗的血液的分析
Analysis of Mitch Romero's blood
揭示了这种物质会治愈
reveals that this substance appears to heal
人体中所有的弱点
any and all weaknesses in the human body,
包括噬血细胞综合征
including HLH.
我需要更多
I need more.
中城医院
罗素医生
Dr. Rosso.
不是故意偷偷靠近你
Didn't mean to sneak up on you like that.
快到万圣节了
Well, it's almost Halloween.
大家都得被吓一吓  不是吗
I guess we're all due for a good scare, right?
你这么晚来有什么事
What brings you here so late?
我来见一个同事
I'm meeting up with a colleague.
我已经比约定时间迟了半小时
Yeah, I told him I'd be here half an hour ago,
所以  失陪了
so...if you'll excuse me.
请便
Of course.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第四集
我希望事情不是如此
I wish it didn't have to be this way.
你就接受这一切了吗
And you're okay with all of this?
没有  但是
No, but...
我必须接受
I have to accept that
还有很多人我们可以拯救
there are still others out there that we can save.
大伙  六周之后
Yeah, guys, look, six weeks from now,
我们都会命悬一线
all of our lives are gonna be on the line,
所以我们必须做好准备
so we have to be prepared.
那他怎么办
Yes, but what about him?
我不会坐等着他
I'm not just gonna wait around
被反物质化成灰烬
for him to get vaporized by anti-matter.
我们应该做些什么尝试去救他
We should be doing something to try to save his life.
你们救不了我
You can't.
你们救不了的  西斯科
You can't, Cisco.
这也是为什么我需要你们不要再为我担心
That's why I need you to stop worrying about me.
如果巴里还有其他的选择
If Barry had any other option,
我们肯定会做的
we'd be doing it.
我想你得接受这个现实
I think you gotta get behind this.
我接受
Yeah. I am.
如何说服你最好的朋友
How do you convince your best friend
不要去救你的命
not to save your life?
你是老师  你会有办法的
You're the teacher. You'll find a way.
他得等一等了
Well, he's gonna have to wait.
是中城警局
It's CCPD.
医疗中心
他来了
There he is.
我今天休假泡汤了
So much for my day off.
-什么情况  -挺诡异的
- What do we got? - It's a creepy one.
有人昨晚闯进了这家医院
Somebody broke into this facility last night,
偷走了十升血
and stole 10 liters of blood.
没有安保摄像吗
There's no security footage?
医院这个区域没有摄像头
There's no cameras in this part of the hospital.
你觉得这和超能力者有关吗
You think this is meta-related?
我还想问你呢
I'm asking you.
超能力者行窃一般会破坏得更严重
Meta-thieves usually make a way bigger mess.
你看这个锁
See this lock?
这种被切开的方式  一把电锯就够了
The way this is sheared, a power saw could've done this.
不好说  可能只是
I don't know. I mean, maybe it was just some
小孩搞的万圣节恶作剧
kids pulling a Halloween prank.
那就好  我还以为
Good. I thought we were dealing
我们遇上超能力吸血鬼了
with some kind of meta-vampire.
只是个脑袋有毛病的普通罪犯
Just a normal criminal with a diseased mind.
作为队长
Well, since I am captain,
我现在要去看下半场比赛了
I'm gonna go watch the second half of the game.
这交给你了  行吗
I'm gonna leave this to you, all right?
好的
Mm-hmm.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好  只是危机即将来临
Yeah. You know, just this Crisis that's coming.
西斯科还不太能接受
Cisco's not taking it so great.
我来猜猜
Let me guess which part.
西斯科和你很相像
Cisco is a whole lot like you.
他天性就想要拯救生命
It is in his nature to want to save lives.
尤其在现在这种情况下
Especially under these circumstances.
回见
I'll see you later.
好的
Right.
谢了  乔
Thanks, Joe.
谢什么
Thanks for what?
我知道怎样说服西斯科了
I think I know how to get through to Cisco.
测试有结果了
Tests are conclusive.
我从米切·罗梅罗身上吸收的奇特黑色血液
The peculiar black blood I absorbed from Mitch Romero
暂时治愈了我血液中的噬血细胞癌
temporarily cured the HLH cancer in my blood,
但那还不足够
but it wasn't enough.
我还需要更多血液
I need more blood
造出完全治愈的药救命
in order to create a permanent cure to save my life.
把罗梅罗的细胞加入这种新血液中
Adding Romero's cells to this new blood
应该是重建我细胞结构的关键
should be the key to rebuilding my cellular structure.
我只希望有足够的时间
I only hope I have enough time.
你为什么没告诉我呢  太厉害了
Why didn't you tell me? It's brilliant.
你是我儿子
You're my son.
你应该让人感到钦佩
You're supposed to be impressed.
你会为这个世界做些美好的事
You're going to do beautiful things for this world.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
妈
Mom?
我的情况已经是末期
My condition is terminal.
我收到你的短信了  怎么了
I got your text. What is it now?
我知道这场危机让你很苦闷
I know you're upset about this Crisis.
我一直在想
And I've been thinking about it,
而且你说得对
and you're right.
我们能做的不仅仅是准备战斗
We can do more than prepare for a fight.
你可以拯救生命
You can save a life.
我就知道你会想通的
I knew you'd come around.
不  西斯科  不是
No, Cisco, not...
不是救我
it's not me.
我们要救拉姆齐·罗素
We're gonna save Ramsey Rosso.
我们先来理一理
Here's the thing.
过去几年来  我们在尖端科研实验室
We've done some insane things at S.T.A.R. Labs
做了一些超越想象的事
over the last few years,
但是治愈罕见的血癌
but curing a rare blood cancer,
我们没有这方面的能力
that is beyond our resources.
所以我们连试都不去试吗
So we just shouldn't try?
那我们尝试  并且成功了
So we try and somehow succeed,
难道我们下半辈子都在这里
are we supposed to spend the rest of your time here
试着去挽救每一个被诊断为癌症的人吗
trying to save everyone who's been diagnosed with cancer?
我们先从一个人开始
We start with one man.
你也听到凯特琳是怎么说拉姆齐的
Look, you heard what Caitlin said about Ramsey.
他是这个地球上最聪明的医生之一
He's one of the most brilliant doctors on the planet.
这件事我需要你的支持
I need you to back me on this.
你很快就会明白了
You'll understand soon enough.
我...
Look, I...
怎样才能治愈噬血细胞综合征
what would it take to cure HLH?
说实话
Honestly...
天神显灵
an act of God.
或者
Or...
科学救人
An act of science.
我知道在哪可以找到
And I know just where to find one.
我猜这位就是你说的那个威尔斯吧
I'm assuming this is the Wells that you were telling me about.
没错  我是纳什·威尔斯
Yep. Nash Wells.
多元宇宙探险家
Multiversal explorer
科学奇迹缔造者
and provider of scientific miracles.
我猜猜
You, I'm guessing,
你就是巴里·艾伦  闪电侠
are Barry Allen, the Flash.
你怎么...  你怎么...
How did he... how did you--
隐形监控设备
Hidden surveillance device.
你监听了尖端科研实验室
You bugged S.T.A.R. Labs?
不  也不算是  我...
No, no, not exactly. I...
我监听了你
I bugged you.
你没有
No, you didn't.
我有
Yeah, I did.
各位  我一直在监听你们的对话
Fellas, I've been listening to your conversations,
我有个提议
and I have a proposition.
我需要一块防震加密电路
Now I need an anti-vibrational crypto-circuit
来完成我在这个地球上的工作
to complete my work on this Earth,
你们需要帮忙完成任务对吧
You need help with your mission, right?
你们帮我做这块电路
Well, you build me my circuit,
因为我知道你们有这个能力
'cause I know you have the capacity,
然后我会带你们去发现一些无价之物
and I will lead you to something priceless
而那些东西会助你们完成任务的
that will surely help your mission.
你的工作
Your work?
-什么工作  -热能挖掘
- What's your work? - It's thermic excavation.
你是宇宙神话揭秘者
You're a cosmic myth-buster
碰巧又是地质学家吗
who also happens to be a geologist?
是的
Sure.
单独说两句
Sidebar.
警惕之市
Red flag city.
是的
Yeah.
还是那句话
Then again...
威尔斯不会无事不登三宝殿的
Wells usually shows up for a reason.
-两位  -嗯
- Fellas? - Yeah.
你们知道我还在监听他吧
You're aware he's still bugged, right?
偷听器在哪  我什么也没看到
Where is the bug? I don't see anything.
不在你鞋子里
Not in your shoe.
-这我可以告诉你  -好吧  我们相信你
- I can tell you that much. - Let's just say that we trust you.
-我们不相信  -很明显我们不相信
- We don't. - Which we obviously don't.
明白了
Understood.
你要给我们什么
What are you offering?
我要给你们一样
I'm offering you something
能帮你们救拉姆齐·罗素的东西
that will help save Ramsey Rosso's life.
我有东西要给你
Have I got something for you.
亚马逊快递包裹吗
Amazon packages?
不是
No.
你这几个月来
You know that case
一直在调查的那个案子
that you've been working on for the last couple months?
那个迪尔邦的女人
The Dearbon woman?
我知道最近没什么进展
Well, I know it's been cold lately,
所以我有个万圣节小礼物要给你
so I have a little Halloween treat for you.
-一条线索  -是吗
- A lead. - Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
我采访了米德韦市的一个会计
I interviewed this accountant in Midway City
苏·迪尔邦
他为一个安保公司工作
that works at the security firm,
他们其中一个保安
and one of their guards
说他曾在一个慈善晚会上工作看到过某个
was working a charity event and claims to have seen someone
像是苏·迪尔邦的人
that sounds like Sue Dearbon,
所以塞西尔请人帮忙弄到了证人报告
so Cecile pulled a favor and got an eye witness report.
棒  谢了  爱瑞丝
Cool. Thanks, Iris.
还需要别的吗
Need something else?
没了
No.
没有  就这些了
No, that was it.
好
Cool.
好吧  好  回头见
All right, yeah. Cool, I will see you later.
血清已经生产完毕
Production of blood serum is complete.
看起来和我从米切·罗梅罗身上
It appears identical to the substance
吸收来的物质相同
I absorbed from Mitch Romero.
如果这个有用
If this works,
我可以治疗不仅我自己
I could hold the cure not just for myself,
还有所有受嗜血细胞癌症侵害的人
but for all those suffering from HLH cancer.
没起作用
It's not working.
我失败了
I failed.
就在那里  麦克洛奇技术公司
It's in there, McCulloch Technologies.
什么在那里
What is?
是一种非常稀有的生物再生血清
Well, this extremely rare bio-regenerative serum
可以治疗器官组织
capable of healing organic tissue,
不管受了什么样的伤都能治
no matter what the harm.
所以你们要用的话  需要做的就是
So for your purposes, what you do,
注射进你朋友的健康细胞中
you simply inject it into your friend's healthy cells,
那些健康细胞自我复制
those healthy cells replicate,
然后替代不健康的细胞
they replace the unhealthy cells.
转瞬之间  速造奇迹
Presto. Instant miracle.
不过  别等到你们的朋友病情太重
Although, don't wait till your buddy's too far gone
因为到那时可能就没用了
because then it might not work.
这个听起来过于理想化了
This sounds way too good to be true.
对  他说的没错
Yeah, he's right.
我是说  麦克洛奇技术公司是怎么
I mean, how did McCulloch Technologies
开发出如此先进技术的
develop something this advanced?
不是他们开发的  是他们偷的
They didn't develop it. They stole it.
是天鹅座星球上来的...
It's from Swan Moon, the--
支配者的母星吗
The Dominator home planet?
对  就是那个
Yeah, that's the one.
是从三年前某次入侵回收来的
Yeah, recovered from some invasion three years ago.
总之  都是些废话
Anyway, blah blah blah.
你们到底加不加入
You guys in, or what?
如果这武器落入错误人的手里
Well, how dangerous a weapon could this be
会有多危险
in the wrong hands?
如果危险程度是从一到十
On a scale of one to ten...
十二
12.
咱们得拿到那东西
We gotta get our hands on this thing.
好吧  我去关闭外围安保摄像头
All right, I'm gonna disable the exterior security cameras.
他直接穿过门出去了
He goes right through the door.
挺酷的
Huh. That's cool.
你怎么知道那些东西在这里的
How'd you know the stuff was here?
孩子   作为多元宇宙探险家
Kid, multiversal explorer.
我们必须了解这些事
We need to know things.
那血清呢
And the serum?
可能保护某人不受反物质影响吗
Could it protect someone from anti-matter?
我想这不用说也知道
I expect that goes without saying.
摄像头关闭了
Cameras are down.
好了  小伙子们
All right, boys.
现在乐趣才开始
Here's where the fun begins.
好了
All right.
极速者  来吧
Speedster, come on.
带我们迅速进入仓库
Speed us to the storage room.
我做不到
No, I can't.
你做不到是什么意思
What do you mean you can't?
这建筑里边充满了
There are localized meta-dampeners
小范围超能力抑制器  好吗
all over this building, all right?
我的能力在这里废了
My powers are useless in here.
也就是说你废了
It means you're useless here.
我们可没必要给你做电路
We don't have to make your circuit.
是这样吗  硬汉
Is that right, tough guy?
你有没有想过如果
Have you thought about what you're gonna do
你不给我做电路  而我不给你...
if you don't make my circuit, and I don't have--
蠢货们  别吵了
Hey, numbskulls, knock it off.
站住  你们俩
Freeze! Both of you.
我们俩
Both of us?
我们可以解释
So we can explain.
我想他们不会先问问题
I don't think they're gonna ask questions first.
纳什
Nash?
伙计们
Hey, fellas.
你们的听觉神经...
So your auditory nerves--
什么
What?
你的耳朵几分钟后就会恢复
Your ears will be fine in a couple of minutes.
这俩就不一样了  现在...
Unlike these two. Now...
我们说到哪了
where were we?
好了  赶紧走吧
All right, let's hurry up.
除了我们还有一个人有生命危险
There's another life at stake besides our own.
拉尔夫
Hey, Ralph.
迪尔邦的线索有什么进展了吗
Any progress on that Dearbon lead?
你知道吗  我真觉得这里边肯定有什么
You know, I really think that there might be something...
秘密
to it.
不  我决定放弃了
No. I decided to give it up.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
根本没意义  爱瑞丝
There's no point, Iris.
苏的案子已经没戏了
The whole Sue thing is a lost cause,
我现在放弃省得浪费时间
so I might as well quit before I waste any more time.
拉尔夫  你不能放弃
Ralph, you can't quit.
你已经痴迷于去找她
You're obsessed with finding her.
你要坚持下去
You have to keep going.
爱瑞丝  抛去闪电小队的口号
Iris, despite Team Flash's mantra,
有时候你应该放弃一些事情
sometimes you do have to give up on things.
我要是你  我就会多花一点时间
You know, if I were you, I would be spending
去陪陪我的老公
a lot more time with my husband...
趁现在还有时间
while he's still here.
已锁定
已解锁
好了
All right.
开始搜吧
Let the search begin.
天哪
Oh, man.
没有超级速度  我们需要找一阵
Without super-speed, this is gonna take a minute.
我们不需要搜索每个区域
We don't have to search every location,
只需找冷的地方
just the cold ones, okay?
因为我们要找的这个血清
Because the serum we're looking for,
需要零下15度的环境
it requires an environment of -15 degrees.
这个写着零下15度
This says -15 degrees.
这就找到了
Well, there you go.
-好了  -真方便
- Okay. - Convenient.
是时候去偷黄金魔像了
Time to steal our golden idol.
你们听到了吗
Did you guys hear that?
什么  没有啊
What? No.
我什么都没听见
I didn't hear anything.
等一下  我也听到了  那是警报吗
Wait, yeah, I did hear that. Is that an alarm?
最好别是  我需要更多时间破解它
It better not be. I need more time to hack this.
我来解决
I'm on it.
-慢点  -好了  我搞得定
- Hey. - Yeah, yeah, I got it.
我去跟着他
I'm gonna follow him.
纳什  纳什  纳什
Nash, Nash. Nash.
好了
Okay.
我不知道他去哪了
I don't know where he went.
-我解开了  -是吗
- I got it. - Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
不
No.
-我们来太晚了  -不  不应该是这样的
- We're too late. - No, this can't be happening.
麦克洛奇肯定先卖出去了
McCulloch must've already sold it.
我们需要这个去救拉姆齐
We needed this to save Ramsey.
伙计们
Boys...
有人来了
we got company.
一直都想这么说
Always wanted to say that.
这里  接住
Here. Catch.
这是什么
What is this?
这个
This...
这个是我们撤离的方法
this is our way out of here.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们应该怎么用这个
What are we supposed to do with this?
很简单  把它扔地上就好了
It's easy. You just throw it.
就像现在
Like, now.
还挺刺激的吧  伙计们
Well, that was exciting, wasn't it, fellas?
休息室  我们是怎么
The Lounge? How did we--
不用担心我们是怎么回到休息室的
Worry less about how we got to the Lounge,
多想想怎么建我的加密电路
and more about building my crypto-circuit.
那是不可能的
That's not happening anymore.
让我纠正你一下  巴里·艾伦
Let me correct you, Barry Allen.
那是可能的
Yes, it is.
我们约定好了  不是吗
We had a deal, right?
我带你们去找一个无价的东西
I would lead you to something priceless,
我也帮你们了  血清不见了又不是我的错
which I did, not my fault the serum was gone.
所以现在  你们两个
So now, you two...
要给我做这个设备
are gonna build me a device.
我不理解
I don't understand.
为什么这个血液又不起效了
Why won't this blood work again?
我漏掉了什么
What am I missing?
我找到了  治疗你的药
I found it, the cure for you.
这个解药的粘合剂是暗物质
The bonding agent in this cure is dark matter.
所以就是这样
So that's it.
你决定放弃  然后等死
You're just deciding to give up and die.
没有人是永生的
No one lives forever.
不
No.
我不会放弃的
I won't give up.
那是你的选择
That's your choice.
拉姆齐
Ramsey.
我不是你的敌人
I'm not your enemy.
我知道
I know.
真正的敌人
The real enemy...
是死亡
is death.
你知道吗  纳什不拿到他的加密电路
You know, Nash isn't going anywhere
是不会走的
until he gets this crypto-circuit.
做得怎么样了
How's it coming?
快完事了
Almost finished.
好吧
All right.
我不觉得你应该做完
I don't know if you should.
你是什么意思
Okay, what do you mean?
我的意思是  你没有觉得这一切
I mean, doesn't something feel off
有些不对劲吗
about all this?
是啊  我知道
Yeah, I know.
那个人突然出现需要我们的技术
The guys shows up needing our tech,
定下一个协定去帮我们
makes a bargain to help us,
然而我们需要的东西碰巧不见了
and conveniently, the thing we need isn't there.
是啊
Right.
那我的意思是
So, I mean...
你觉得他在说谎吗
you think he's lying to us?
不是第一次姓威尔斯的有秘密目的了
It wouldn't be the first time a Wells had a secret agenda.
是啊
Yeah.
这里是什么
Yo, what's in here?
给冰霜准备的存货
That's storage for Frost's stuff.
你知道她会出现什么情况
You know how she gets.
从我进来你就没直视过我
You haven't looked me in the eye since I came in here.
等下
Wait.
这到底是什么
What the hell am I looking at?
西斯科
Cisco.
你很清楚这是什么
You know exactly what this is.
我不在乎你有什么能力
I don't care what powers you have.
你想要
You want it...
你得先过我这一关
you're gonna have to go through me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我在救你
I'm saving your life.
因为总得有人这么做
'Cause someone has to do it.
救拉姆齐
Saving Ramsey...
救拉姆齐是我的决定
saving Ramsey's my call.
不是好决定
And it's a bad call.
但是我做的决定
But it's the one I made.
有时候作为领导者  你需要做艰难决定
Sometimes, as a leader, you have to make tough calls
这样才能维持大局
in order to serve the greater good.
我做了一个艰难的决定
You know, I made a tough call.
为你而做的
And I made it for you.
但我告诉你了  你不能救我
But I told you. You can't save me.
我不信
I'm not buying that.
你得相信
Well, you have to.
牺牲我能拯救一切
Sacrificing myself saves everything and everyone.
我看到了
I've seen it.
那有什么能让我期待的
And what does that give me to look forward to?
面对一个没有闪电侠的世界
Waking up to a world without the Flash?
一个没有我好朋友的生活吗
A life without my best friend?
你能活下去
You get to live.
你们都能活下去
You all get to live.
别
Don't.
听着  我
Look, man, I...
我这几周都在消化这个事情
I've been dealing with this for weeks.
想知道我离开之后会发生什么
Wondering what's gonna happen when I'm gone,
大家如何继续
how everybody's gonna move on.
这就是为什么我想要今天你和我
That's why I wanted us, you and me together,
我们一起救拉姆齐
to save Ramsey today.
你想我们随便救个人
You wanted us to save a random person
然后我就能接受你的死吗
so I'd be okay with you dying?
不是
No.
我想我们救一个人
I wanted us to save one person's life
这样你就能理解困难的决定
so you could understand the tough calls...
领导者要做的牺牲
the sacrifices that a leader has to make.
因为你是我选择的接班人
Because you're my pick.
我想要你在我离开后
You're the person that I want to run S.T.A.R. Labs
管理尖端科研实验室和这个小队
and this team when I'm gone.
一整天  我一直在尝试教你
All day, I've been trying to teach you
这些责任有多困难
how hard those responsibilities can be.
但是你偷了那个
And then you stole something
能够救他人一命的东西
that was meant to save another person's life.
甚至还为此辩解
You justified it, even.
再来一次  我还会这么做
And I'd do it again.
或许我做了错误的选择
Maybe I made the wrong choice.
血清是你的了
The serum's yours.
巴里
Barry.
我们能聊下吗
Can we talk?
现在真的不是好时候
Um, now's really not a good time.
这很重要
It's important.
我有个东西需要给你
I have something that I need to give you.
尖端科研实验室一直在研究
S.T.A.R. Labs has been doing some research
再生配方  我们开发了一种血清
into regenerative formulas, and we've developed a serum.
我们认为这能够救你一命
We think that this could save your life.
如果你把它注入你健康的细胞
If you inject it into your healthy cells,
它们会进行复制  最终压制
they'll duplicate and eventually overtake
你被HLH感染的细胞
your cells that are affected by HLH,
但你得尽快使用
but you have to use it quickly.
它是
Is it...
它是基于暗物质吗
is it dark-matter-based?
不  是实验性的  但...
No, it's experimental, but...
我们相信能治愈你
we believe it'll cure you.
我已经放弃希望了
I'd given up hope.
但为什么为了我这么做
But why--why do this for me?
一周前  你告诉我你感觉在跌下悬崖
A week ago, you told me you felt like you were falling off a cliff.
我希望你能有个救生索
I want you to have a lifeline.
你也要死了
You're dying, as well.
你自己不想要救生索吗
Don't you want a lifeline for yourself?
这只够一个人
There's only enough of this for one person.
我读到过你  拉姆齐
And I've read about you, Ramsey,
我也和凯特琳谈过
and I've talked to Caitlin.
你是一个优秀的医生
You're a brilliant doctor.
据她所说  如果你有足够的时间
From what she said, if you had enough time,
你能够治愈HLH
you could cure HLH.
我把这个时间给你
I'm giving you that time.
世界需要你这样的人
The world needs people like you
来拯救不能自救的人
to save those who can't save themselves.
试试吧
Test it.
证实我们所相信的功效
Verify what we believe it'll do,
然后尽快使用
and then use it quickly.
我们不确定这个血清有效时限是多久
We're not sure how long the serum will be viable.
巴里
Barry.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在忙吗
You busy?
为了你  队长
For you, Cap?
我永远都不忙
Never.
爱瑞丝说  你在迪尔邦的案子上遇到了麻烦
Iris tells me you've been having trouble with the Dearbon case.
乔  我从去年夏天就开始
Joe, I've been working on this Dearbon thing
调查迪尔邦的案子
since last summer.
然后我突然醒悟了
Then it dawned on me.
现在继续调查已经没有意义了
Digging into this right now, it doesn't matter.
我到底为什么要找到她
Why the hell should I try to find her
还要帮助她
and try to help her...
如果我都救不了
If I can't even save...
巴里  你可以说出他的名字
Barry. You can say it.
巴里
Barry.
拉尔夫
Ralph.
你记得我以前的搭档查尔吗
Do you remember my old partner Chyre?
他教给我一个重要的道理
He taught me an important lesson.
他说  "你不可能拯救所有人"
He said, "You can't always save everyone..."
"但你总能拯救某个人"
"But you can always save someone."
对你来说
For you...
这个人就是苏·迪尔邦
that's Sue Dearbon...
不是巴里
not Barry.
我会想他的  乔
I'm gonna miss him, Joe.
就是这个吗
That's it?
功能完备的加密电路
Fully functioning crypto-circuit?
你确定吗  它看起来有点
You sure? 'Cause it kind of seems like...
有点劣质  粗制滥造
seems kind of shoddy. Shoddy workmanship.
我在其它地球上见到的
I feel like I've seen better workmanship on,
制造工艺都比这个好
well, pretty much all the other Earths out there.
这个低于平均水平
This is subpar.
低于平均水平都算夸奖了
Subpar's being generous.
它...  别碰我
It-- never touch me.
就凑合用吧
Just take it.
当然  孩子
Sure, kid.
多谢  下次冒险再见
Thanks. Till our next adventure.
小冰霜
Frosty.
那么
So...
和极速者教授谈得怎么样了
how'd it go with Professor Speedster?
准备好开始后危机时代的生活了吗
You all ready for life post-Crisis?
我想我们的友谊就要结束了
I think our friendship pretty much exploded.
因为没有办法救他
Because it is impossible to save him,
但是  我认为我不应该放弃尝试
and yet, I still don't think I should stop trying.
想听听我的建议吗
You want some free advice?
当然
Sure.
你无法拯救不想被拯救的人
You can't save someone who doesn't want to be saved.
他已经做出决定了
And he's already made up his mind.
如果你继续坚持的话
And if you obsess over it,
可能会走上一条黑暗的道路
it could lead you down a dark path.
也许会犯下无法弥补的错误
You might make a mistake you can't fix.
开始对尖端科研实验室解药进行初步测试
Commencing preliminary tests on S.T.A.R. Lab's proposed cure.
该死
Damn it!
当然又失败了
Of course it's another failure.
我为什么会期待不同的结果
Why would I expect anything different from the universe?
我的命运已经无法改变
My fate is sealed.
死亡又一次胜利了
Death wins again.
死亡
Death.
有一处关键的区别
There is one key difference.
太迟了
Too late.
我偷来的血
Between the blood I stole,
与米切·罗梅罗的血的不同之处在于
and the blood from Mitch Romero's body.
罗梅罗正因死亡感到恐惧
Romero was afraid for his life.
他的血细胞中充满了肾上腺素
His blood cells were flooded with epinephrine.
受到袭击时释放的肾上腺素
Adrenaline released during the attack,
就是粘合剂
it's the bonding agent,
也就是说
which means...
为了创造活下去所需的物质
In order to create the substance I need to live,
我得杀人
I have to kill.
但首先
But first...
他们要感到恐惧
they have to be afraid.
希波克拉底誓词
不害人
中城总医院有多个警报  他们正在疏散
Multiple alarms at Central City General. They're evacuating.
是炸弹威胁吗
Is it a bomb threat?
报告称有一个疯子在袭击患者
Reports say a madman is attacking patients.
中城医院
撤离程序
所有其他员工和患者都撤出了
All the staff and patients are accounted for,
除了在这一层里的
except for those on this floor.
这个伤口是新的  凶手刚刚就在这里
That one's fresh. Whoever did this was just here.
为什么有人会做出这种事
Why would someone do this?
她死了
She's gone.
也许我能找到原因
Maybe I can figure out why.
快去
Go.
癌症病房
问讯处
肿瘤门诊
化疗康复
拉姆齐  你在做什么
Ramsey? What the hell are you doing?
为了活下去所必需做的
Whatever it takes to stay alive.
这些人  你就是凶手
These people. You're the one that's killing.
尖端科研实验室给了你解药
S.T.A.R. Labs gave you a cure.
你为什么不用
Why didn't you take it?
我用了
I did.
但是没有用
But it didn't work.
我人类血液中的疾病已经无药可救了
Turns out the disease in my human blood was too far gone.
但是如果我变成非人类
But if I was to become something more than human,
我意识到自己可以永生
that's when I realized I could live forever.
只要我吸食能量
As long as I feed.
拉姆齐  你是个医生
Ramsey, you're a doctor.
你应该救人  而不是杀人
You're supposed to save lives, not take them.
我在拯救生命  闪电侠  我的命
I am saving lives, Flash. Mine.
现在  你挡住了我的路
And right now, you are in my way.
拉姆齐  别这样  放他走  求你了
Ramsey, come on, let him go. Please.
不行
I can't.
我的血亲兄弟姐们不仅能帮助我
My blood brothers and sisters are much more than just the help.
还能让我变得更强壮
They're making me stronger.
你在利用他们
You're using them.
为了生存
To survive.
你好  凯特
Hello, Cait.
现在开始扮英雄了  是吗
Playing the hero now, are you?
坏人的角色被占了  所以是的
The bad guy was taken, so yeah.
求你了  救救我
Please, help me.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
你速度很快  闪电侠
You're fast, Flash.
但作为医生  我知道这人颈动脉的确切位置
But as a doctor, I know exactly where this man's carotid artery is.
即使我不能吸食
Even if I can't feed,
你也来不及救活他了
you will never save him in time.
拉姆齐  别这样
Ramsey, don't do this.
让我们帮你
Let us help you.
你这样做...
What you're doing, it's...
太没人性了
inhuman.
正是我的人性在拖我后腿
It was my humanity that was holding me back.
妨碍我成为那个
Preventing me from becoming the man
妈妈一直知道我注定会成为的人
Mum always knew I was destined to be.
她总是说我会为这个世界做些
She always said that I would do beautiful things
美好的事
for this world.
她说得对
And she was right.
因为过去的我才是疾病
Because the man I was, that was the disease.
有使用期限的脆弱人体
A frail human body with a shelf life.
正在腐烂
Rot.
但我找到了战胜这一切的方法
But I found a way to transcend all that.
就是战胜死亡本身
To defeat death itself.
人人都会死  拉姆齐
Everyone dies, Ramsey.
也许唯一让其不那么难以接受的方法就是
Maybe the only thing that makes it bearable
在其中寻找出意义
is to find some meaning in it.
好  这意味着我作出了最伟大的牺牲
Well, that means I'm making the greatest sacrifice of all.
你看不到吗
Don't you see?
我变成了什么  这就是治疗方法
What I'm becoming, this is the cure.
我就是答案  闪电侠  能解开最大的谜团
I am the answer, Flash, to the greatest mystery of all.
生命永恒
Life eternal.
求你了  罗素医生
Please, Dr. Rosso.
我把你留到最后
I saved you for last
这样你就会是最害怕的人
so you would be the most afraid.
拉姆齐  请别这样
Ramsey, please don't do this.
你本可以救我妈妈  但是你没有
You could've saved Mum, but you didn't.
所以我要来找你
And that's why I came here for you.
拉姆齐
Ramsey.
坚持住  好吗  有我在  有我在
Stay with me, all right? I got you, I got you.
他们到底在干什么
What the hell are they doing?
我觉得他们想跟随拉姆齐
I think they're trying to follow Ramsey.
等等
Wait.
-我们必须帮他  -我觉得我们帮不了
- We have to help him. - I don't think we can.
我们输了
We lost.
今晚有五个人无法回家与家人团聚
Five people aren't going home to their families tonight.
而第六位  拉姆齐
And the sixth, Ramsey.
我们也失去了他
We lost him, too.
他在外面不知所踪  我们必须阻止他
He's out there somewhere. We have to stop him.
我...
I...
我必须阻止他
I have to stop him.
-巴里  -你本来想要救他
- Barry. - You tried to save him.
但他把自己变成了怪物
But he turned himself into a monster.
这不是我们的错  是拉姆齐自己的选择
That's not on us. That was Ramsey's choice.
我发誓  只要我还活在
I swear, if it is the last thing I do
这个世界上...
on this Earth...
我就要阻止他
I'm gonna stop him.
拉姆齐究竟是靠什么做出这种事的
How did Ramsey do this, anyway?
他用人做培育器
He's using people as incubators.
用他们的身体来培育维持他生命的物质
Using their bodies to create what he needs to keep himself a live.
所以他把那些人变成了人体血液银行
So he's turning people into human blood banks.
只要他饿了
And as soon as he gets hungry again--
就去那里"取款"
He's gonna make a withdrawal.
好吧  万圣节快乐  各位
Well, happy Halloween, everyone.
好吧
Yeah.
拉尔夫
Hey, Ralph.
听着
Look...
我知道任何人都很难接受这个危机的消息
I know this Crisis news hasn't been easy on anyone.
是的
Yeah.
我同意
I'll say.
但听着  爱瑞丝
But look, Iris...
这不是我犯浑的借口
that's no excuse for me being a jerk.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道你只是想帮我
I know that you were just trying to help me.
所以我想说明天我就给中途城打电话
So I did want to say that tomorrow I'm call Midway City,
看看有什么发现
see what I can find.
那太好了  拉尔夫
That's great, Ralph.
苏很幸运
Sue is very lucky to have
有你这样优秀的侦探去寻找她
a master detective like you searching for her.
饶了我吧
Give me a break.
不过是个失踪案件而已
It's just a missing persons case.
我又不是要找对象
It's not like I'm looking to get married.
他会没事吗
He gonna be okay?
会的
Yeah, he is.
那么多晚惧怕发生这样的疯狂事件
Of all the nights for this madness to be happening,
偏偏发生在了万圣节
it had to be Halloween.
宝贝  我们可能该回家了
Babe, we should probably head home.
你先走  我几分钟后再赶上来行吗
Would you mind if I catch up with you in a couple minutes?
不介意
No.
没事
It's fine.
巴里
Barry.
我要为麦克洛奇那件事道歉
I'm sorry about what happened at McCulloch.
不  兄弟  听着  这个...
No, man, no. Look, this...
这不是你的错
this is not your fault.
我本该集中精力拯救该救的人
I should've been focused on saving the right person.
我是说  尽管拉姆齐的事情
Well, I mean, even though things didn't...
没能得以解决  至少我们尝试了
work out with Ramsey, at least we tried...
去做对的事情
to do the right thing.
我仍不知道你怎么做到的
I still don't know how you do that, man.
振作自己  努力向前
Picking yourself up, pushing forward.
我只是试着
I'm just trying to...
去教你我花了很多年学习的东西
teach you what it's taken me years to learn.
我知道你在为了我们这么做
I know you're doing it for all of us.
这就是做英雄的意义
That's what it means to be a hero.
我知道我选了对的人
I knew I picked the right guy.
我就...
I'm gonna...
好  我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm good.
乔
Hey, Joe.
你还好吗
You all right?
我就是
I was just...
就是在想拉姆齐在哪
just wondering where Ramsey was and...
向上帝祈祷我们在事情恶化之前
just hoping to God that we find him before...
找到他
this gets worse.
他的速写已经传遍了
Well, his description has been circulated
从这里到高谭的每一个警局
to every precinct from here to Gotham,
所以我们应该能找到他
so we should find him.
那之后呢
Then what?
更多的人会受伤
More people are gonna get hurt.
或者更差
Or worse.
我知道
I know.
我试着拯救他了
I tried to save him.
想着多做点好事  在我...
Tried to do some good before I...
不准你开始这样说
Don't you dare start talking like that.
你做了很多好事了
You've done plenty of good.
自从你变成了闪电侠
Ever since you became the Flash,
你比中城警局所有人加起来救的还多
you've saved more people than CCPD altogether.
没有你  我早就...
Without you, I would've...
我早就失去我们的家人了
I would've lost our family a long time ago.
这就是你一次又一次拯救世界的所得吗
And this is what you get for saving the world over and over again?
怎么
How...
这怎么能是对的
how is that right?
你知道世界不是这么运转的
You know it doesn't work like that.
不是吗
Doesn't it?
我是个警察
I mean, I'm a cop.
如果我30年来每天冒着生命危险
If I risk my life every day for 30 years,
巴仔  我能退休
I get to retire, Barr.
我能回到家陪我爱的女人
I get to go home to the woman I love.
我能自豪的看着我的宝贝女儿
I get to proudly watch my baby girl
每天茁壮成长
grow up each and every day.
我能有生活  巴仔
I get a life, Barr.
你是个英雄  你得到了什么
You're a hero. What do you get?
什么都没有吗
Nothing?
这就是...
It's just...
可恶  这不对
Damn it. It's not right.
我们  这个世界
We--the world...
这个世界欠你的
the world owes you.
你值得更好的
You deserve better than this.
不  我不值得
No, I don't.
我为我有的所有事物满怀感激
I'm grateful for everything that I have.
我这一生中所获得的幸福
All the blessings in my life.
我感激爱瑞丝  这团队
For Iris, the team.
我是说...
I mean, hell...
我是闪电侠
I'm the Flash.
我很感激
I'm grateful for that.
但是你
But you...
但是你才是我最感激的
You're what I'm most grateful for.
如果不是你
If it weren't for you...
你的耐心  你的勇气
your patience, your courage...
继续前进的意志
The will just to keep going.
我从你身上学到了全部这些
I learned all that from you.
比其他任何人都多  在团队之前
More than anyone else, before the team,
在艾瑞丝之前
before Iris...
你是那个展示给我
you were the one that showed me
做一个好人
what it takes just to...
需要些什么
be a good person.
你是我能够成为闪电侠
You're one of the biggest reasons
最重要的原因之一
I was even able to become the Flash.
而为了这些  我会一直充满感激
For that, I'll always be grateful.
巴仔  我还没准备好
Barr, I'm not ready.
我无法面对这事
I'm not ready for this.
这不是
It's not...
没事  没事的
It's okay, man. It's all right.
不  我知道你
No. I know you...
我知道你说这必须要发生  但是
I know you say it has to happen, but...
没事的
It's all right.
没事
It's okay.
我永远不会离开你
I'm never gonna leave you.
就算我死了
Even when I'm gone.
我们试试这个
Let's try this.
原来你一直藏在这里
So this is where you've been hiding.
是上门拜访的时候了
Time to pay a house call.